DERRICK ZZIWA

Kampala, Uganda 🏦

+256-754893983

derricktab44@gmail.com

✓

linkedin.com/in/derrick-zziwa in

derricktab.github.io

github.com/derricktab (





INTRODUCTION

Innovative and deadline-driven software developer with 2+ years of experience designing and developing user-centered software from initial concept to final, polished deliverable. I have used a range of languages, operating systems, and development tools as well as experiencing the system development life cycle. Specializing in artificial intelligence and mobile technology, I am keen to make interesting products in software development.



EDUCATION

Bachelor Of Computer Science | Kabale University

2019 - 2023

Data Structures and Algorithms, Operating Systems, Web and Mobile Programming, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Simulation and Modelling, Computer Organization and Architecture.

Certificate In Machine Learning | Google AI – Explore ML

MAY 2021 – AUGUST 2021

Computer Vision, TensorFlow, OpenCV, Matplotlib, NumPy.

Certificate In Cyber Security | Cisco Networking Academy

JAN 2021 - JUNE 2021

Encryption, Cryptography, Ethical Hacking.



EXPERIENCE

Chief Technical Officer | Qriscorp (U) Limited

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

✓ Leading technology strategy, driving innovation, and ensuring technical excellence for growth.

Software Developer | Qriscorp (U) Limited

DEC 2022 - MAY 2023

✓ Flutter, React JS, Firebase, Google Analytics, REST APIs, Python.

Mobile App Developer Intern | Y0 Uganda Limited

JAN 2022 – MAR 2022

✓ Mobile Application Development, BitBucket, PHP, REST APIs MySQL.

Junior Software Engineer | Tabzilic Technologies

JUNE 2021 – DECEMBER 2021

- ✓ Systems analysis with clients to determine requirements talking to managers and staff and observing work practices throughout the supply chain
- ✓ Analysis of data including modeling
- ✓ Part of a software development team creating a stock control system linking mobile devices to warehouse systems
- ✓ Demonstrating prototypes to staff
- ✓ Field testing, implementation, and evaluation
- ✓ Participating in final project reporting
- ✓ Contributing to English language documentation and training

Web Developer | IBO Associational Group Ltd

DEC 2020 – JUNE 2021

- ✓ Website Development (Html, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, jQuery, Bootstrap)
- ✓ Web hosting (cPanel)
- ✓ Logo designing



SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python, Dart, JavaScript, Java, C++, SQL, PHP, and HTML.
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, MacOS, and Android.
- Frameworks: Flutter, Bootstrap, React JS.
- Technologies: Docker, Google Cloud Platform, Cloud Firestore, TensorFlow, OpenCV, FastAPI, Firebase.

GENERAL SKILLS

- Excellent interpersonal / communications skills.
- Ability to work independently and as part of a wider team.
- Ability to multi-task and stay organized in a dynamic work environment.
- Ability to pay attention to detail.

ACTIVITIES

- 2nd Best out of more than 2,000 applicants in the Africa IOT & AI challenge, representing my country Uganda at the finals in Dubai.
- Google Developer Students Club Lead for Kabale University from Aug 2021 Aug 2022.
- Principal Investigator of the Malnutrition Digital Assistant Project, an AI-based mobile application for the quick diagnosis of malnutrition in children below 5 years.
- Co-Investigator of the V-Chemlab, a virtual chemistry simulator for making chemistry practicals fun.
- Worked on a self-driving autonomous obstacle detection and avoidance robot to deliver drugs in hospitals.
- Research Lead for Youth Mappers, Kabale University Chapter from 2021 2022.
- Member of Data Science Africa.
- Member of DevCareer Africa.
- Member of Black In Al.



REFERENCES

References Available on Request